Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Yamato...
You gave us hope for our revolution.
Why do you protect the remnants of Desler ?
It doesn't matter !
Destroy any ship that opposes us !
Another wave !
Twelve missiles from above !
Intercept !
Don't miss a single one !
Bow torpedoes, fire !
Don't stop !
Split up into the three ships !
All of those ships will head to Earth,
so just get on any one of them !
Don't get hit by those stray missiles
until all the refugees are brought aboard.
More ships detected in the gas clouds.
They appear to be reinforcements.
Reinforcements ?!
No, that ID is...
Those are interplanetary ballistic missiles.
How did they obtain such things ?
Destruction, revolution, war...
They occur in any civilization.
After these meaningless cycles, a critical
mistake brings about self destruction in the end.
That's laughable.
For nations, families, convictions...
...for love, humans steal and kill.
That's unbearable to watch.
Humans will only obtain true happiness and
eternal peace thanks to our genuine love.
We are Gatlantis.
Our lives are deliberately manufactured.
Incoming message from the Garmillas ship, warning us that the rebel force might use interplanetary ballistic missiles.
If they use those on this unstable planet...
Nanbu, main guns No. 1 and No. 2...
Wait !
If we attack now, burning debris
could rain down on the refugees.
Emergency ascent !
The Yamato will act as a decoy !
Manufactured lives...?!
Humanoids that are designed for war...
....although, the civilization that created us is no more.
Those who named us Gatlantis
and looked down on us have all died off.
You mean, you destroyed them ?
We, as individuals, do not
possess the ability to reproduce.
Therefore, we're free from the complexity of love.
Only Gatlantis can bring real peace
to the universe, in the way that suits us.
You are a warrior of the Yamato.
You were summoned by Teresa.
No, Teresa should never
have called on the likes of you.
What are you talking about ?
Pitiful...
You lost your way because of the poison called emotion.
You don't know what love is.
Because of love, people die, planets perish,
and the universe ceases to exist.
Exactly what you have done
with your ship, Kodai Susumu.
How did you...?
You have lost so many precious things...
...that's why you are afraid of...
...your loved one dying.
The large missiles stopped
at an altitude of 500 meters.
That Zoellugut-class ship at the center must be guiding the missiles to their optimal positions.
If so...
We still have a chance.
Status on the Garmillas refugee ships ?
About to take off.
Good. Stand by main guns.
Bow wave motion shield, maximum output !
Roger !
You must know...
...what humanity's true salvation is.
It must be hard to live with the fear of loss.
You may ask for our help.
The Garmillas ships have launched.
Open a path for them,
then destroy the large missiles !
Prepare for shock wave.
Fire !
Unit 3 !
Yamato...
Fire !
This occurs as I talk.
After all, humans need our guidance.
With our true love, that can't be swayed by individual favor, that's in harmony with the nature of the universe.
Freedom from oppression, independence
and self governance for all humanity...
Fire !
Righteousness is on our side !
Maintain stability !
How's the wave motion shield ?
No problem.
Good. Attack only the
enemy ship's bow for now.
Shima, main engine maximum output !
Roger !
This is a noble fight to end
Garmillas' unreasonable oppression.
Do not be afraid of dying !
This planet will break apart soon.
Shima, stay at the lowest altitude that's still
safe for the ship, and hold until Kodai returns.
O...okay.
Chief Engineer Tokugawa.
Engine room, stand by for escape at any moment.
Aihara, tell the Garmillas ships that we'll stay in this sector
until we recover our crewman, so they should go on ahead.
Roger.
Good luck to them, too.
Stay in the safe zone.
We must confirm the safety of "that person."
I didn't expect the rebels to go this far.
I can...
...I can feel...
...human thoughts...
...and the egos that come
from the illness called "emotion."
We, Gatlantis, must put an end to this
repetitious tragedy using Teresa's grace.
What's the connection between you guys and Teresa ?
I'll show you what your love will allow to live and die.
I have placed reanimated bodies from the dead on
each of the Garmillas ships carrying refugees to Earth.
Reanimated bodies...?!
Yuki !
This is also a reanimated body, and it can
turn to fire, just like the Gatlantis soldiers.
I'll save one ship, and you will make the choice.
If you don't, all three will lose their
engines and share in this planet's fate.
Say what...?
Be faithful to your love and make the choice.
Kodai !
Are you hurt ?
Saito...
Hijikata ordered me to come here.
What the hell was that ?
Kodai !
Kodai, what's wrong ?
Only one...only one ship can survive.
What ?
What're you talking about ?
Gatlantis humanoid bombs are on
all three of those ships, but only one ship...
Hey, Kodai !
I have to choose. That's their rule.
This is Kodai. Yamato, do you copy ?
Kodai, so you're safe.
Mr. Hijikata...
As soon as Kodai and Saito are back, leave this zone.
To the Garmillas fleet ?
That's right, Aihara.
On an open channel ?
I want you to relay this communication to the
refugees on the Garmillas ships. It's an emergency.
Do it.
Lieutenant Keyman, ask the Garmillas ships to approve.
Aye, sir.
Everyone, our desire was to rescue
you on the 11th Planet and take you to Earth.
However, the situation took an unexpected turn.
I'm...I'm very sorry.
Whatever happens...
Whatever happens, Lieutenant Mori
will be with you all the way to Earth.
Yuki...
Yuki, do you read me ?
I owe you so many apologies.
I was afraid of losing you by
bringing you on this dangerous journey.
No, that's not all.
I was just so happy being by your
side that nothing else mattered.
People on Earth won't do what they're
supposed to do, and I could become that way.
I was afraid of it.
That's why I distanced myself from you.
But you boarded the Yamato,
and knowing that made me feel happy.
I was happy, just happy, and there was no reason for it.
I'm such a pathetic, weak, and selfish man.
Kodai.
What happens next has nothing to do with you.
I want you to live.
I can't stand losing you...
...regardless of how heavy the
burden of my sin will be, I...
What happened, Kodai ?
Kodai !
Please respond, Kodai !
Ms. Nagakura.
Lieutenant Mori ?
What's wrong ?
Saito, what's going on ?
What happened in the ruins ?
What is Kodai talking about ?
King of Gatlantis, you can hear me, can't you ?
I'll choose...
Is that Miss Mori ?
What is she doing ?
Yuki...
Kodai, once you make the choice,
you'll never forgive yourself.
Kodai, I won't allow you to choose.
Yuki !
I won't choose ! I won't !
Kodai !
To prevent him from making a choice ?
Changing the rules is unacceptable.
W...what happened ?
Engine stopped ! We can't
control the ship ! We're falling !
Increase the output !
I can't ! At this rate, we'll be caught
in the corruption of the planet !
The Garmillas ships that took our refugees...!
Abnormality detected at the core of the planet !
Corruption of its gravity
field seems to have begun !
This is the result of your choice.
Your human arrogance to not make a
choice will kill those you could have saved.
So empty. I feel so empty.
Yuki !
Yuki...
Yuki.
Acting Captain Kodai's signal detected,
but there's no mass in that location !
They aren't there ?
Analyzer, calculate the falling trajectories of the Type-100 and Garmillas ships and calculate the intersection point.
Roger.
Mr. Sanada, that point could...
Right.
If we insert a mass that's equal to the planet...
...its energy conversion will stop the gravitational storm, which will push Kodai and the others out.
It's a risky bet.
There's a chance that both the Yamato and the Garmillas ships will get caught in the gravitational epicenter.
Let's do it.
I missed the chance to give my business card to the Gatlantis leader on the 11th planet.
If he's watching, let him learn how
determined and resilient humans are.
Analysis complete,
sending data to the captain's chair.
Prepare to fire the wave motion gun !
Target scope open !
Okita, let me borrow your ship.
Target the core of Stravase's inner sphere.
Yuki...
Kodai...
You dummy.
Yuki...
...will you marry me ?
How many times do I have to say yes ?
Don't ever let me go again.
This is Yamamoto of the Cosmo Tigers.
Both of them are alive.
Sabera...
...must we do this again ?
Episode 9
Zorder's Demonic Choice
Kienai de aoi tsuki yo
Blue moon, please don't fade away
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Analyzer:
Saijo Miki:
Yamamoto Akira:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Chiba Yuki
Mugihito
Cho
Moriya Satomi
Tanaka Rie
Terashidasu kimi hitohira
It lights up my love just enough
Saito Hajime:
Shiori Nagakura:
Hijikata Ryu:
Katsuragi Touko:
Keyman:
Zorder:
Monk:
Skipper:
Operator:
Touchi Hiroki
Amagai Kazusa
Ishizuka Unsho
Kaida Yuko
Kamiya Hiroshi
Tezuka Hideaki
Sawaki Ikuya
Fujinuma Kento
Yano Masaaki
Nani hitotsu kawaranai
Everything was routine
Monotone iro no hibi
Monotone days for so long
Unmei ga tsurete kita
Fate brought you to me
Kimi no me ni koi wo shita
I fell in love with your eyes
Chikaku ni kanjitai yo
I want to feel you close
Atatakai te ni furete
Touching your warm hands
Aa sugu ni kotoba ni dekitara
Wishing I could put this into words right away
Konnani ai shiteru
I love you so much
Kakurenai de koigokoro yo
Loving feelings, please don't hide
Kimi dake terashiteru yo
It sheds light only on you
Konya nara sou ieru
I can say that because tonight is different
Preview
Are they going to devour the system ?
Operation Chief Mori, we have a problem.
Acting Captain Kodai is...
I want to be on a ship where I can fight.
Take back what you said.
I won't say anything.
I've arranged the gift you desire most.
Episode 10
Deceptive Space Fireflies Bring Danger